Werner Seligmann Papers
Werner Seligmann Papers
- Project records
  - WILLARD STATE HOSPITAL REHABILITATION CENTER (WRC) 7116 County Route 132 Willard, New York (not built) [Health]
    - Drawings, 1970; working drawings (Tube 170)
    - Drawings, 1970; site plan and details (Tube 171)
    - Model, plexiglass cover, good condition; approximate dimensions: 34.5"L x21"W x11"H. "Werner Seligmann and Associates, Frederic P. Wiedersum Associates, Architects" (Box Model-8)
    - Presentation board 77, hospital campus plan
    - Presentation board 78, axonometric/plan
    - Presentation board 79, elevations, section
    - Presentation board 80, sections, "WRC"; "A8
    - Presentation board 81, north and east elevations, "WRC"; "A7"
    - Presentation board 82, sections, "WRC"; "A10"
    - Presentation board 83, south and west elevations, "WRC"; "A6"
    - Presentation board 84, sections, "WRC"; "A9"
    - Presentation board 85, basement plan, "WRC"; "A5"
    - Project material, 1969; sections, plans, axonometrics, model; map; text from exhibition board (Box 64)
    - Project material, oversize (Box 94C)
    - Slides, title slide (dated 1971), site plans, axonometrics, elevations, analysis or explanatory diagrams, plans, models, earlier; 75 (Box S-5)
  - WOODBURN COURT PROPOSAL, Binghamton, New York (not built) [Government]
    Proposal for development of housing. Sponsor/client: Binghamton Urban Renewal Authority (BURA). Collaborators/partners: Associated Architects/Personnel: John Cummings, Stephen Dragos, Robert Holdsworth, Brian Kessler, Michael Murphy
    - Drawings, 1971-1972; base maps, preliminary drawings (Tube 172)
    - Presentation board 24, section, elevations
    - Presentation board 25, site plan, scheme 3
    - Presentation board 26, site plan
    - Project material, 1971; site analysis, elevation, sections; memo (Box 26)
    - Slides, site plans, sections; 20 (Box S-5)
  - XVII TRIENNALE DI MILANO EXHIBITION Milan, Italy (1987) (not built) [Government]
    Invited entry to large international exhibition. Assigned area involved via Stalingrado, a major street connecting the historic center of Bologna to the periphery. Sponsor/client: Italian Government.
    - Drawings, 1966-1985; base documents and maps (in Italian) (Tube 173)
    - Drawings, undated; presentation drawings (Tube 174)
    - Drawings, undated; presentation drawings (Tube 175)
    - Project material, 1985-1986; sections; correspondence (some in Italian); competition materials; financial; narrative of project (Box 79)
    - Slides, title slide (dated 1987), site plans, axonometrics, sections, referential images; 4 (Box S-5)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified projects
    - Drawings, undated (Tube 176)
    - Slides, includes paintings by WS (dated 1955); pictures of WS; models, general views; "Hub for Brooklyn"; another school (Hugh Gregg School); unidentified projects; 20 (Box S-5)
- Writings and biographical material
  - American Institute of Architects (AIA): Topaz Medallion Award, 5/11/1998; seligmann_w_001; videotape accompanied by speech transcript; VHS; running time 2:17 (Box 96)
    Introduction, Seligmann's acceptance speech.
  - Scrapbook I (Box 87)
    Scrapbook I includes photos and plans of Beth David Synagogue, Ithaca Commons Center, Ithaca Scattered Site Housing - Elm St., Olean Central Fire Station, Science Building II (SUNY Cortland), Willard State Hospital and Administration Building and Rehabilitation Center.
  - Scrapbook II (Box 88)
    Scrapbook II includes plans, sections, elevations of the Arizona Historical Society Museum Design Competition, Ft. Lauderdale Riverfront Plaza Design Competition, Monroeville Area Civic Center Competition, Opera de la Bastille Competition, Prinz-Albrecht-Palais Competition, Tokyo International Forum Competition, Topography of Terror Competition, XVII Triennale di Milano Exhibition, miscellaneous clippings.
  - Scrapbook III (Box 89)
    Scrapbook III includes lists of Seligmann's honors, awards, publications, exhibitions, experience, projects, competitions; miscellaneous clippings regarding Ithaca Commons Center, Ithaca Scattered Site Housing - Elm St. and Maple Ave., Olean Central Fire Station, Science Building II (SUNY Cortland), Willard Administration Building and Rehabilitation Center.
  - Writings by and about Seligmann, articles, list of competitions, exhibitions, publications, biographical materials, etc. (Box 86)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966-1997 (Box 93)
    This material includes correspondence, awards and lectures, reports, magazines, clippings and sketches. Projects represented include Beth David Synagogue, Ithaca Commons Center, Science Building II (SUNY Cortland), and Willard State Hospital Administration Building and Rehabilitation Center.